Guide to the International Center for Transitional Justice (ICTJ) records, 1918-2020, bulk 1970-2020 RL.01304
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Program and Subject Files, 1979-2015
  - ICTJ Programs, 1979-2014
    - Truth and Reconciliation Commissions: Audiovisual Materials
      - Liberia
        - Liberia Truth and Reconciliation Commission Thematic and Institutional Hearings at the Centennial Pavilion, Monrovia, 2008-02-19; Mini-DV (Box 141, Video-cassette RL01304-MDV-0432)
          #131 Grand Kru Day 2, Alex Toe Sieh
        - Liberia Truth and Reconciliation Commission Thematic and Institutional Hearings at the Centennial Pavilion, Monrovia, 2008-02-19; Mini-DV (Box 141, Video-cassette RL01304-MDV-0433)
          #132 Grand Kru Day 2, Theophilis Molmgee Jugbe
        - Liberia Truth and Reconciliation Commission Thematic and Institutional Hearings at the Centennial Pavilion, Monrovia, 2008-02-20; Mini-DV (Box 141, Video-cassette RL01304-MDV-0434)
          #133 Grand Kru Day 3, Helena Saydee
        - Liberia Truth and Reconciliation Commission Thematic and Institutional Hearings at the Centennial Pavilion, Monrovia, 2008-02-20; Mini-DV (Box 141, Video-cassette RL01304-MDV-0435)
          #134 Grand Kru Day 3, Helena Saydee (duplicate)
        - Liberia Truth and Reconciliation Commission Thematic and Institutional Hearings at the Centennial Pavilion, Monrovia, 2008-02-20; Mini-DV (Box 141, Video-cassette RL01304-MDV-0436)
          #135 Grand Kru Day 3, Victoria Blidee Wreh
        - Liberia Truth and Reconciliation Commission Thematic and Institutional Hearings at the Centennial Pavilion, Monrovia, 2008-02-20; Mini-DV (Box 141, Video-cassette RL01304-MDV-0437)
          #136 Grand Kru Day 3, Augustine G. Nyanfor
        - Liberia Truth and Reconciliation Commission Thematic and Institutional Hearings at the Centennial Pavilion, Monrovia, 2008-02-20; Mini-DV (Box 141, Video-cassette RL01304-MDV-0438)
          #137 Grand Kru Day 3, Jeremiah Slehn Nagbe
        - Liberia Truth and Reconciliation Commission Thematic and Institutional Hearings at the Centennial Pavilion, Monrovia, 2008-02-20; Mini-DV (Box 141, Video-cassette RL01304-MDV-0439)
          #138 Grand Kru Day 3, Emmanuel Quanteh Sebo
        - Liberia Truth and Reconciliation Commission Thematic and Institutional Hearings at the Centennial Pavilion, Monrovia, 2008-02-20; Mini-DV (Box 141, Video-cassette RL01304-MDV-0440)
          #139 Grand Kru Day 3, Robert Kieh Kieh
        - Liberia Truth and Reconciliation Commission Thematic and Institutional Hearings at the Centennial Pavilion, Monrovia, 2008-02-20; Mini-DV (Box 141, Video-cassette RL01304-MDV-0441)
          #140 Grand Kru Day 3, Robert Kieh Kieh (duplicate)
        - Liberia Truth and Reconciliation Commission Thematic and Institutional Hearings at the Centennial Pavilion, Monrovia, 2008-02-20; Mini-DV (Box 141, Video-cassette RL01304-MDV-0442)
          #141 Grand Kru Day 3, Annie Nimene
        - Liberia Truth and Reconciliation Commission Thematic and Institutional Hearings at the Centennial Pavilion, Monrovia, 2008-02-20; Mini-DV (Box 141, Video-cassette RL01304-MDV-0443)
          #142 Grand Kru Day 3, Mary I. Nagbe
        - Liberia Truth and Reconciliation Commission Thematic and Institutional Hearings at the Centennial Pavilion, Monrovia, 2008-02-20; Mini-DV (Box 141, Video-cassette RL01304-MDV-0444)
          #143 Grand Kru Day 3, Sylvester S. Nimene
        - Liberia Truth and Reconciliation Commission Thematic and Institutional Hearings at the Centennial Pavilion, Monrovia, 2008-02-20; Mini-DV (Box 141, Video-cassette RL01304-MDV-0445)
          #144 Grand Kru Day 3, Felicia Gray
      - Morocco
        - Morocco IER, 2004; CD (Box 136, Cd RL01304-CD-0085)
          CDs in Arabic
        - Morocco IER, 2004; CD (Box 136, Cd RL01304-CD-0086)
        - Morocco IER, 2005; CD (Box 136, Cd RL01304-CD-0087)
        - Morocco IER, 2005; CD (Box 136, Cd RL01304-CD-0088)
        - Morocco IER, 2005; CD (Box 136, Cd RL01304-CD-0089)
        - Morocco IER, 2005; CD (Box 136, Cd RL01304-CD-0090)
        - Morocco IER, 2005; CD (Box 136, Cd RL01304-CD-0091)
        - Morocco IER, 2005; CD (Box 136, Cd RL01304-CD-0092)
        - Morocco IER, 2005; CD (Box 136, Cd RL01304-CD-0093)
        - Morocco IER, 2005; CD (Box 136, Cd RL01304-CD-0094)
        - Morocco IER, 2005; CD (Box 136, Cd RL01304-CD-0095)
        - Morocco IER, 2005; CD (Box 136, Cd RL01304-CD-0096)
        - Morocco IER, 2005; CD (Box 136, Cd RL01304-CD-0097)
        - Morocco IER, 2005; CD (Box 136, Cd RL01304-CD-0098)
      - Peru
        - To Reflect on the Past and the Future, VHS (Box 128, Video-cassette RL01304-VHS-0170)
          Peru CVR
        - The Displaced/Civil Society Resistance, the Case of Puno (NTSC 5), 2002-10-30; Betacam-sp (Box 129, Video-cassette RL01304-Bcam-0005)
        - The Judiciary During the Internal Conflict (NTSC 7), 2002-06-21; 2002-07-04; 2002-09-25; Betacam-sp (Box 129, Video-cassette RL01304-Bcam-0007)
        - The Magistery and the University Community (NTSC 8), 2002-10-30; 2002-11-28; Betacam-sp (Box 129, Video-cassette RL01304-Bcam-0008)
        - The Role of a Commissioner-Spanish Version, Betacam (Box 131, Video-cassette RL01304-Bcam-0026)
        - The Role of Civil Society in The Truth and Reconciliation Process, VHS (Box 127, Video-cassette RL01304-VHS-0131)
        - The TRC Before the National Audience (NTSC 12), 2002-04-08; 2003-03-09; 2003-06-06; Betacam-sp (Box 129, Video-cassette RL01304-Bcam-0012)
        - The Truth and Reconciliation Commission: The Public Hearings, 2002-04-08/2002-04-08; CD (Box 136, Cd RL01304-CD-0002)
        - Spot Iniciativa Sobre Personas Desaparecidas Campaña "para que no te olvides", CD (Box 136, Cd RL01304-CD-0068)
        - Spot: "Campaña sobre Desaparecidos", Cassette (Box 134, Audio-cassette RL01304-CS-0027)
        - Spots: "Comision de la Verdad y Reconciliacion", 2002-03-02; Cassette (Box 134, Audio-cassette RL01304-CS-0030)
        - Resumen de Audiencia Publica Comunidad Universitaria y Violencia Policitica, 2002-10-30; VHS (Box 128, Video-cassette RL01304-VHS-0184)
        - Sendero Luminoso's Terror (NTSC 11), 2002-04-08; 2002-06-21; 2002-08-27; 2002-09-10; Betacam-sp (Box 129, Video-cassette RL01304-Bcam-0011)
        - Sesion Especial, 2003-06-10; VHS (Box 123, Video-cassette RL01304-VHS-0019)
          series from the Peruvian CVR
        - Sesiones Institucionales de Balance y Perspectivas, 2003-06-12; VHS (Box 123, Video-cassette RL01304-VHS-0015)
          Partido Aprista Peruano (series from Peruvian CVR)
        - Sesiones Institucionales de Balance y Perspectivas, 2003-06-10; VHS (Box 123, Video-cassette RL01304-VHS-0016)
          Partidos de Izquierda (series from Peruvian CVR)
        - Sesiones Institucionales de Balance y Perspectivas, 2003-06-11; VHS (Box 123, Video-cassette RL01304-VHS-0017)
          Partido Popular Cristiano (series from Peruvian CVR)
        - Sesiones Institucionales de Balance y Perspectivas, 2003-06-11; VHS (Box 123, Video-cassette RL01304-VHS-0018)
          Partidos Accion Popular (series from Peruvian CVR)
        - Peru Truth Commission Conference at the UN, 2003-06-17; CD (Box 138, Cd RL01304-CD-0219)
        - Peasant and Native Communities Between Fires (NTSC 9), 2002-04-11; 2002-05-25; 2002-08-27; 2002-12-12; Betacam-sp (Box 129, Video-cassette RL01304-Bcam-0009)
        - Ponder on the Past Build on the Future, CD (Box 136, Cd RL01304-CD-0016)
        - Ponder on the Past Build on the Future, CD (Box 136, Cd RL01304-CD-0017)
        - Ponder on the Past Build on the Future, CD (Box 136, Cd RL01304-CD-0018)
        - Ponder on the Past Build on the Future, CD (Box 136, Cd RL01304-CD-0019)
        - Popular Leaders Under the Political Violence (NTSC 10), 2002-04-08; 2002-05-22; 2002-06-21; Betacam-sp (Box 129, Video-cassette RL01304-Bcam-0010)
        - Informe Final, 2003; CD (Box 136, Cd RL01304-CD-0036)
          Final Peru CVR report
        - Lucanamarca Programa de TV RTP Canal 7, 2002-12-15; VHS (Box 127, Video-cassette RL01304-VHS-0157)
        - Lucanamarca Programa de TV RTP Canal 7, 2002-12-15; VHS (Box 127, Video-cassette RL01304-VHS-0158)
        - Human Rights in Peru, 2003; CD (Box 136, Cd RL01304-CD-0080)
          Documents released by the CVR
        - API Violencia Política y en el Altiplano, VHS (Box 127, Video-cassette RL01304-VHS-0155)
        - APT Violencia Política y Comunidad Universitaria, VHS (Box 127, Video-cassette RL01304-VHS-0156)
        - Peru Commission Victims, Mini-DV (Box 139, Video-cassette RL01304-MDV-0019)
        - Peru Commissioners, 2003-06-18; Mini-DV (Box 139, Video-cassette RL01304-MDV-0059)
        - Peru CVR 1: "CADs, Self Defense Comms and Political Violence", Mini-DV (Box 140, Video-cassette RL01304-MDV-0258)
          Dubs from Beta
        - Peru CVR 10: "Popular Leaders Under the Political Violence", Mini-DV (Box 140, Video-cassette RL01304-MDV-0267)
        - Peru CVR 11: "Sendero Luminosos Terror", Mini-DV (Box 140, Video-cassette RL01304-MDV-0268)
        - Peru CVR 12: The TRC Before the National Audience", Mini-DV (Box 140, Video-cassette RL01304-MDV-0269)
        - Peru CVR 13: "Women as Protagonists", Mini-DV (Box 140, Video-cassette RL01304-MDV-0270)
        - Peru CVR 2: Children, Reparations, Amazon proposal, Mini-DV (Box 140, Video-cassette RL01304-MDV-0259)
        - Peru CVR 3: Citizens under Arbitrariness, Mini-DV (Box 140, Video-cassette RL01304-MDV-0260)
        - Peru CVR 4: "Direct Actors in the Conflict", Mini-DV (Box 140, Video-cassette RL01304-MDV-0261)
        - Peru CVR 5: "The Displaced/Civil Society Resistance", Mini-DV (Box 140, Video-cassette RL01304-MDV-0262)
        - Peru CVR 6: "Excesses in the Fight Against Sendero", Mini-DV (Box 140, Video-cassette RL01304-MDV-0263)
        - Peru CVR 7: "The Judiciary During Internal Conflict", Mini-DV (Box 140, Video-cassette RL01304-MDV-0264)
        - Peru CVR 8: "The Magistery and the University Community", Mini-DV (Box 140, Video-cassette RL01304-MDV-0265)
        - Peru CVR 9: "Peasant and Native Communities Between Fires", Mini-DV (Box 140, Video-cassette RL01304-MDV-0266)
        - Peru CVR Reflexionar sobre el Pasado construit el futuro, VHS (Box 127, Video-cassette RL01304-VHS-0160)
        - Peru TRC "Women as Protagonists", Mini-DV (Box 139, Video-cassette RL01304-MDV-0012)
          dubbed from Beta
        - Peru Truth Commission, 2002-10-30; Mini-DV (Box 139, Video-cassette RL01304-MDV-0010)
        - Peru Truth Commission, Mini-DV (Box 139, Video-cassette RL01304-MDV-0043)
        - Peru Truth Commission (tape 2), 2002 April; VHS (Box 127, Video-cassette RL01304-VHS-0164)
        - Fotos: CVR, CD (Box 138, Cd RL01304-CD-0218)
        - CADs, Self Defense Committees and Political Violence (NTSC 1), 2003-05-16; Betacam-sp (Box 129, Video-cassette RL01304-Bcam-0001)
        - CAVR (Tetum), Decusse/Public Hearing, CAVR (English), 2003 February; CD (Box 136, Cd RL01304-CD-0069)
          East Timor TRC
        - CAVR East Timor-Public Audience Hearings, CD (Box 136, Cd RL01304-CD-0107)
        - Children During Political Violence Reparation/Proposal for the Amazon Region (NTSC 2), 2002-04-08; 2002-05-22; 2002-05-25; 2002-09-10; Betacam-sp (Box 129, Video-cassette RL01304-Bcam-0002)
        - Citizens Under Arbitrariness (NTSC 3), 2002-08-08; 2002-09-10; 2002-05-25; Betacam-sp (Box 129, Video-cassette RL01304-Bcam-0003)
        - Closer to the Truth rough cut, VHS (Box 128, Video-cassette RL01304-VHS-0199)
        - Comisión de la Verdad, CD (Box 136, Cd RL01304-CD-0065)
        - Comisión de la Verdad y Reconciliación Espots en Castellano-Quechua, 2002-03-02; Cassette (Box 134, Audio-cassette RL01304-CS-0031)
        - Comisión de la Verdad y Reconciliación Espots en Castellano-Quechua, 2002-03-02; Cassette (Box 134, Audio-cassette RL01304-CS-0032)
        - Comision de la Verdad y Reconciliación: Desenterrando la verdad en Chuschi, VHS (Box 123, Video-cassette RL01304-VHS-0024)
          From Peruvian CVR
        - Comision de la Verdad y Reconciliación: Grupos de Trabajo, VHS (Box 123, Video-cassette RL01304-VHS-0025)
        - Comision de la Verdad y Reconciliación: Microprogramas 1-18, VHS (Box 123, Video-cassette RL01304-VHS-0021)
        - Direct Actors in the Conflict (NTSC 4), 2003-06-10/2003-06-12; Betacam-sp (Box 129, Video-cassette RL01304-Bcam-0004)
        - Dr. Alone Challenge TRC, 2003-03-30; Cassette (Box 134, Audio-cassette RL01304-CS-0034)
        - Excesses in the Fight Against Sendero (NTSC 6), 2002 April- 2002 November; 2002-05-22; 2002-06-21; 2002-10-30; Betacam-sp (Box 129, Video-cassette RL01304-Bcam-0006)
        - Final Report, DVD (Box 132, Dvd RL01304-DVD-0005)
        - Audencias Publicas: Abancay, 2002-08-28/2002-08-29; VHS (Box 123, Video-cassette RL01304-VHS-0005)
          Series from the Peruvian CVR
        - Audencias Publicas: Comunidad Educativa y Violencia Politica, 2002-11-28; VHS (Box 123, Video-cassette RL01304-VHS-0010)
        - Audencias Publicas: Comunidad Educativa y Violencia Politica, 2002-11-28; VHS (Box 123, Video-cassette RL01304-VHS-0011)
        - Audencias Publicas: Comunidad Universitaria y Violencia Politica, 2002-10-30; VHS (Box 123, Video-cassette RL01304-VHS-0004)
        - Audencias Publicas: Desplazamiento Forzado y Violencia Politica, 2002-12-12; VHS (Box 123, Video-cassette RL01304-VHS-0012)
        - Audencias Publicas: Huancayo y Huancavelico, 2002-05-22/2002-05-26; VHS (Box 123, Video-cassette RL01304-VHS-0009)
        - Audencias Publicas: Huanta, 2002-04-11/2002-04-12; VHS (Box 128, Video-cassette RL01304-VHS-0187)
        - Audencias Publicas: Legislacion Antiterrorista y Violacion al Debido Proceso, 2002-07-04; VHS (Box 123, Video-cassette RL01304-VHS-0006)
        - Audencias Publicas: Legislacion Antiterrorista y Violacion al Debido Proceso, 2002-07-04; VHS (Box 123, Video-cassette RL01304-VHS-0007)
        - Audencias Publicas: Tingo Maria, 2002-08-08/2002-08-09; VHS (Box 123, Video-cassette RL01304-VHS-0008)
        - Audencias Publicas: Trujillo, 2002-09-25/2002-09-26; VHS (Box 123, Video-cassette RL01304-VHS-0003)
        - Audencias Publicas: Violencia Politica y Crimenes Contra la Mujer, 2002-09-10; VHS (Box 123, Video-cassette RL01304-VHS-0002)
        - Audiencia Publica de Huancayo, VHS (Box 128, Video-cassette RL01304-VHS-0188)
        - Audiencia Publica de Huanta, VHS (Box 127, Video-cassette RL01304-VHS-0161)
        - Audiencia Publica de Trujillo, VHS (Box 128, Video-cassette RL01304-VHS-0185)
        - Audiencias Publicas, 2002-06-21/2002-06-22; VHS (Box 128, Video-cassette RL01304-VHS-0186)
      - Sierra Leone
        - Sierra Leone TRC, Mini-DV (Box 139, Video-cassette RL01304-MDV-0058)
          Damaged
      - Solomon Islands
        - Solomon Islands TRC launch (DVD 1), 2009-04-29; DVD (Box 132, Dvd RL01304-DVD-0044)
          4 DVDs all say Tutu on them
        - Solomon Islands TRC launch (DVD 2), 2009-04-29; DVD (Box 132, Dvd RL01304-DVD-0045)
          5 DVDs all say Tutu on them
        - Solomon Islands TRC launch (DVD 3), 2009-04-29; DVD (Box 132, Dvd RL01304-DVD-0046)
          6 DVDs all say Tutu on them
        - Solomon Islands TRC launch (DVD 4), 2009-04-29; DVD (Box 132, Dvd RL01304-DVD-0047)
          7 DVDs all say Tutu on them
      - South Africa
        - S. Africa Truth Commission, 1997; Mini-DV (Box 139, Video-cassette RL01304-MDV-0009)
        - SA Truth Commission, Mini-DV (Box 139, Video-cassette RL01304-MDV-0062)
        - Truth and Reconciliation Commission of South Africa Report, 1999 March; CD (Box 136, Cd RL01304-CD-0026)
        - Truth Commission S. Africa Tutu Cries, 1998-07-25; 1998-10-29; 1998-07-31; DVD (Box 132, Dvd RL01304-DVD-0043)
        - Truth Commission's Hearings in SA (SABC) report tape 2, VHS (Box 126, Video-cassette RL01304-VHS-0124)
        - We Never Give Up, 2002; VHS (Box 126, Video-cassette RL01304-VHS-0096)
          South African Truth Commission
      - Sri Lanka
        - Sri Lankan TC Reports #2, CD (Box 136, Cd RL01304-CD-0022)
      - Uganda
        - Uganda Commission Report, 1975; CD (Box 136, Cd RL01304-CD-0021)
      - United States
        - 24th Anniversary of the Klan/Nazi Killings Nov 4, 1979 Greensboro, NC, 2003-11-01; VHS (Box 128, Video-cassette RL01304-VHS-0196)
        - 24th Anniversary of the Klan/Nazi Killings Nov 4, 1979 Greensboro, NC, 2003-10-31; 2003-11-01; VHS (Box 128, Video-cassette RL01304-VHS-0197)
        - 24th Anniversary of the Klan/Nazi Killings Nov 4, 1979 Greensboro, NC, 2003-10-31; VHS (Box 128, Video-cassette RL01304-VHS-0198)
        - Greensboro Truth and Reconciliation Commission First Public Hearing, 2005-07-15/2005-07-16; DVD (Box 132, Dvd RL01304-DVD-0001)
        - Greensboro Truth and Reconciliation Commission Second Public Hearing, 2005-08-26/2005-08-27; DVD (Box 132, Dvd RL01304-DVD-0002)
        - Greensboro Truth and Reconciliation Commission Third Public Hearing, 2005-09-30/2005-10-01; DVD (Box 132, Dvd RL01304-DVD-0003)
        - GTCRP Press Conference, 2003-01-15; VHS (Box 128, Video-cassette RL01304-VHS-0180)
      - Yugoslavia
        - Justice at Work: an introduction to the work of the International Criminal Tribunal for the Former Yugoslavia, 2001; VHS (Box 125, Video-cassette RL01304-VHS-0094)
        - ICTY Case Transcripts, 2000; CD (Box 136, Cd RL01304-CD-0020)
        - ICTY Website, CD (Box 136, Cd RL01304-CD-0070)
    - Truth and Reconciliation Commissions Electronic Records
      Truth commission materials, including audio and video recordings of trials, commission events, workshops, transcripts interviews, and documents. Materials are from truth commissions in Ghana, Liberia, Iraq, and Uganda. Many of the audiovisual files are digitized from audiovisual media described above.
      - Advocacy, 2002-2008; 31 audiovisual files; approximately 34.3 GB.
        Includes two folders with documentary clips, video interviews, and events, produced by ICTJ and others, related to advocacy, activism, and awareness of Truth and Reconciliation Commissions. One folder contains General advocacy on transitional justice in Ghana, South Africa, and other countries. Another folder contains video interviews, music, footage from events, and other audiovisual material related to the TRC in Liberia.
      - Transcripts, circa 2000-2010; 535 document files; approximately 40.5 MB. (Digital-materials RL01304-SET-0011)
        Contains transcripts of proceedings from commissions in Ghana, Liberia, Morocco, and Peru.
      - Ghana NRC MPEG-4 CONVERSIONS, circa 2000-2010; 44 audiovisual (MP4 format) files; approximately 17 GB. Larger QuickTime video files also exist (approximately 186 gigabytes; RL01304-SET-0013). (Digital-materials RL01304-SET-0012, Digital-materials RL01304-SET-0013)
        Audiovisual material related to the National Reconciliation Commission in Ghana. The footage includes testimonies by government officials and other witnesses and multicamera video footage of the hearings and other proceedings.
        The video files in SET-0013 are considered preservation masters and are close to use.
      - Liberia TRC hearings, circa 2000-2010; 122 audiovisual files; approximately 56 GB. Higher quality video files also exist (approximately 1.49 terabytes; RL01304-SET-0015). (Digital-materials RL01304-SET-0014, Digital-materials RL01304-SET-0015)
        Audiovisual material related to the TRC hearings in Liberia. The hearings took place in the capital city of Monrovia, located in the Montserrado county. The footage includes testimonies by government officials and other witnesses. There are some issues with the audio quality. Also includes reports for database files.
        The video files in SET-0015 are considered preservation masters and are close to use.
      - Desmond Tutu visit to Solomon Islands, 2009; 9 audiovisual files; approximately 57.8 GB. (Digital-materials RL01304-SET-0016)
        Multicamera and documentary video footage of Desmond Tutu's visit to Solomon Islands. Includes speeches, events, and other ceremonies related to the TRC launch in Solomon Islands.
      - Uganda video interviews and transcripts, 2007; 18 audiovisual files; approximately 4.14 GB. (Digital-materials RL01304-SET-0017)
        Video interviews conducted by ICTJ in Uganda with accompanying transcripts. Includes interviews with students, academics, a child soldier, and others.
      - Peru TRC Edited Public Hearings, 2009; 100 video files; approximately 2 gigabytes (use copies) and 119 gigabytes (preservation copies). (Digital-materials RL01304-SET-0018)
        Video interviews in MP4 (use copies) and QuickTime (preservation copies) formats.
  - ICTJ Publications, 2001-2014
    Contains ICTJ publication series, ICTJ annual reports, handbooks, policy briefs, transitional justice publications, and books published by ICTJ.
    - Case Study Series, 2004-2005; 1 folders (Box 103)
      Topics include: Sierra Leone TRC, Argentina and accountability, Bosnian developments in transitional justice, Serbia and Montenegro developments in transitional justice.
    - Conference Report Series, 2006; 1 folders (Box 103)
      Includes reports from conferences hosted by ICTJ.
    - Gender Justice Series, 2006-2015; 1 folders (Box 103)
      Topics include: truth commissions and gender, enforced disappearance and women, sexual violence, Nepal's conflict and women.
    - Occasional Paper Series, 2003-2007; 6 folders (Box 103)
      Topics include: providing reparations in Indonesia, Iraqi Voices, transitional justice in sub-Saharan Africa and the Congo, Indonesian and East Timor peace processes and trials, NGOs and truth commissions, Croatian developments in transitional justice, ICC, Ghana's NRC, restitution.
    - Prosecutions Case Studies Series, 2006-2008; 2 folders (Box 103)
      Topics include: war crimes in Serbia, Bosnia, and East Timor, the Special Court for Sierra Leone, lessons in using international judges in Kosovo.
    - Reparative Justice Series, 2005-2013; 1 folders (Box 103)
      Topics include: reparations in Darfur and Peru, reparations in theory and practice.
    - Truth and Memory Series, 2012; 1 folders (Box 103)
      Topics include: indigenous rights and truth commissions.
    - ICTJ Annual reports, 2001-2014; 4 folders (Box 103)
      ICTJ annual reports, strategic plans, and strategic perspective, ICTJ fact sheets.
    - ICTJ non-serial publications, 2003-2013; 13 folders (Box 104)
      Publications include: practitioners handbooks and manuals, survey on attitudes about peace in Uganda, truth commissions, criminal tribunals and justice, transitional justice and democracy in Latin America, Cambodian communities in transition, policy briefs, Lebanon's political violence and special tribunal, peace in the DRC, children and transitional justice.
    - ICTJ published books, 2001-2009; 11 folders (Box 104-105)
      Includes Unspeakable Truths by ICTJ's Priscilla Hayner, essays about transitional justice, truth commissions and procedural fairness, democracy in postcolonial Sri Lanka, reparations and the Darfur peace process, truth, memory, and reconstructions, reparations for victims of political violence, justice for systematic crimes, prosecuting heads of state, transitional justice and development.
  - ICTJ Conferences/Workshops, 1997-2015
    Conferences, workshops, courses, seminars, and symposia hosted by ICTJ in various locations throughout the world.
    Arranged in chronological order.
    - Conferences, Workshops, Courses, and Symposia, 1997-2015; 91 folders (Box 105-107, Box 145)
      Contains files, trip reports, conference reports, and workshop notes from conferences hosted by ICTJ or ICTJ in partnership with another NGO.
      Arranged chronologically: box 105 1997-2002, box 106 2002-2007, box 107 2007-2015. Additional materials dated from 2000s in Box 145.